# Derek Chan. Jarvis Consulting

From Seneca College, I graduated with a Honours Bachelor of Technology - Software Development, over the years studying in the program, I learned practical software development technologies and skills such as Docker, Linux Shell Scripting, Agile/Scrum and software application design. Previously, my experience was related to project and processes management at a condominium development consulting company where my focus was spent streamlining workflow processes, making sure that projects were proceeding in a timely manner and managing communication between teams and execution of project steps. My knowledge of software development includes Java, Springboot, SQL, Docker, AWS/GCP, and Git/Github. As a budding junior developer, I am always looking into the possibilities of producing software that will assist in running my life and contributing to my career development.

#### Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: Spring Boot, JIRA, Javascript, IntelliJ IDEA IDE, Apache Maven Familiar: Google Cloud Platform, Amazon Web Services, CI/CD, Python, Docker

#### Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/Jarvis-Consulting-Group/jarvis\_data\_eng-drkcn94

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Developed a monitoring agent program using Bash scripting for recording of hardware specifications and resource utilization of linux clusters. The program was implemented using Bash scripting, Docker, PostgreSQL, and crontab. Testing of the application was done using bash's debugging features with the flag -x and with logging of errors to stderr to temporary log files. Deployment of the application was done by Dockerizing the PostgreSQL database management software and the adding the host\_usage.sh script to crontab to continuously record and insert data regarding hardware usage to the database.

# Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

Twitter App: Not StartedJDBC App: Not StartedGrep App: Not Started

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not Started
Spark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

#### **Highlighted Projects**

Web app for Badminton Club Managemment and Player Statistics (Shuttlestats): Currently Developing a Passion Project to assist Badminton Club/Group Managers and myself with management duties including recording payment history of players, attendance of sessions, and player match history/statistics including total win/loss record, and partner win rate/synergy.

## **Professional Experiences**

Junior Software Developer, Jarvis (2023-present): Onboarded as a software developer to Jarvis assist and develop software solutions for clients and training. The work environment requires an understanding and usage of Agile/Scrum and open, positive mindset for continuous growth and understanding of software development.

Business Operations Assistant, MBRA Canada Inc. (2022-2023): Lead the development of workflow processes and maintaining communications among various teams and companies working on condominium developments. Workflow processes required the knowledge of folder structures and scripting to automate the saving of legal documents and condominium files. Daily reporting was done to all stakeholder individuals/companies to make sure that everyone had the

same details regarding projects. Continuous research was done to understand if the workflow processes implemented were suitable for the working circumstances and standards of clients or improvements were required.

## Education

Seneca College (2018-2022), Honours Bachelor of Technology, School of Software Design and Data Science - GPA: 3.4/4.0

#### Miscellaneous

- Training for Badminton for over a decade, always looking to improve on how I play
- I love reading about the next destination to travel to
- Growing up with a Dad that loved building computers, I got into it as well and always look into the latest consumer computer technology and building custom PCs